Guide to the Edward F. Morrissey Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Edward F. Morrissey papers
1974-1984
MS 798
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
The papers consist of correspondence, memoranda, and reports relating to health care policies and programs in Connecticut during the 1970s and early 1980s. In his capacity as program co-ordinator of the Connecticut Regional Medical Program, executive director of the Southwest Connecticut Health Systems Agencies, and consultant for the United Way, Edward F. Morrissey was involved in the analysis of the existing health care system and the formulation and implementation of changes relating to health care financing and delivery. The papers form part of the Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection.
Morrissey, Edward F.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Edward F. Morrissey, 1977 and 1989.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in chronological order.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, memoranda, and reports relating to health care policies and programs in Connecticut during the 1970s and early 1980s. In his capacity as program co-ordinator of the Connecticut Regional Medical Program, executive director of the Southwest Connecticut Health Systems Agencies, and consultant for the United Way, Edward F. Morrissey was involved in the analysis of the existing health care system and the formulation and implementation of changes relating to health care financing and delivery. The papers form part of the Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection.
Medicine; Public health administration; Public health; Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection; Morrissey, Edward F.; Connecticut Association for Human Services; Connecticut Regional Medical Program
- General correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 4)
- Connecticut Social Welfare Conference (CSWC), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Connecticut Association for Human Services (CAHS) [previously CSWC]
  - "Preliminary Report, Program Evaluation", 1975 May (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Preliminary Report to CAHS Board," by consultant Paul Nagle [evaluation of CAHS], 1976 January 14 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Interim Evaluation," by Paul Nagle, 1976 February-September (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Human Service Organization: Problems and Proposals"
    - First draft and revisions, 1976 July-August (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Final version, 1976 September (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Finances [for research of human services programs], 1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Improving the Delivery of Health and Social Services (Human Services) by the State of Connecticut" [report of the Select Advisory Panel on Human Service Organization of CAHS], 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Committee on the Structure of State Government (CSSG) [also known as the Filer Committee], 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Council on Human Services, 1976 February-April (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Institute of Health project, 1977 Feb, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Greenwich United Way [community forum paper, "Consolidation of the Human Services agencies within Connecticut's State Government: 'The Why and the How' "], 1977 January (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Human Services Reorganization Commission ["Human Services Plan: Discussion Draft"], 1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- United Way of Southeastern Connecticut, Inc.
  - "USN Sub-Base, Groton, Connecticut: A Proposal for a Human Services Counselling Center", 1979 August (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "The Adolescent In Crisis: A First Response Network for Southeastern Connecticut", 1979 November (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "The Child Protection Coordinator: An Appraisal", 1980 February (Box 2, Folder 20)
- State Health Coordinating Council (SHCC)
  - Request for grant from Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "New Arrangements for Health Planning in Connecticut: A Concept Paper", 1982 January-February (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Southwest Connecticut Health Systems Agency
  - Assessment of SHCC proposal, "New Arrangements for Health Planning in Connecticut", 1982 January (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "Health Systems Plan for Southwest Connecticut", 1982 February (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Demise of agency, 1982 May-July (Box 2, Folder 25)
- United Community Services (UCS), Norwich ["Seeking Strength Through Shared Services: The Future Direction of Home Care in New London County"], 1984 (Box 2, Folder 26)